# Ronny Haase



**9** London, United Kingdom

On request On request

I'm developing web based solutions for 15 years, focused but not limited to frontend development for the past 6 years. I offer excellent knowledge and multiple years of experience with designing, developing, testing and optimizing scalable web solutions.

I've been working as engineer, trainer and consultant with companies and agile teams of different size and experience, also in lead roles.

## **Key Skills**



#### Work Experience

04/2018 - Today Paws.com

London, United Kingdom

Lead Frontend Software-Engineer

- Build of first release of mobile-first web app within 2 months
- Further major releases, improvements and cleanup
- Scaling and leading Frontend team

## 07/2016 - 12/2016 DaWanda GmbH

Berlin, Germany

Lead Full-Stack Software-Engineer & Frontend Chapter Lead

- Leadership of Frontend Chapter Alignment, planning, staff development, training, line management
- Defining and designing software architecture for rebuilt of whole platform, esp.
  Frontend
- Pair & Mob programming with whole engineering dept. to teach, and establish alignments for, frontend and architecture

07/2016 - 12/2016 Zalando SE

Berlin, Germany

Senior Frontend Software-Engineer

- Test-driven, full-stack development in agile team
- Frontend: Multiple Universal microfrontend web apps with ReactJS & Redux
- Backend: Multiple Microservices with NodeJS
- All systems running live and in production on AWS using CD & CI

# 11/2013 - 06/2016 StayFriends GmbH

Berlin, Germany

Senior Frontend Software-Engineer

- Worked in multiple, agile, cross-functional teams, partly in leading role
- Lead & developed UI rebuilt for member area as SPAs with AngularJS
- Training the whole engineering department on AngularJS, JavaScript, frontend engineering & architecture
- Renewed performance critical, SEO optimized public pages using Progressive Enhancement
- Back-end development with Java & JSP on Tomcat, advocating Service-Oriented Architecture

# 07/2013 – 10/2013 Freelancer

Germany

Frontend Developer / Web Application Developer & -Architect

Beside parental leave supported multiple smaller projects of the government with my frontend knowledge:

- Coaching about and improving responsive and adaptive web solutions
- · Improved responsiveness of an official city page
- Implemented frontend for Cordova based city guide app

## 07/2012 - 06/2013 the a-team GmbH

Berlin, Germany

Frontend Developer

- Built solutions for core–product used by leading multinational tourism companies using jQuery, Bootstrap and BackboneJS
- Introduced more modern frontend architecture, libraries & tools and service oriented architecture
- Also back-end development with PHP and DevOps

#### 09/2011 – 06/2012 Freelancer

Germany

Frontend Developer // Web Application Developer & -Architect

Developed of the frontend for a web application for online reviewing catalogues and special offer flyers for one of Germanys biggest chain of drug stores.

08/2004 - 08/2011 Freelancer Berlin, Germany

Web Application Engineer & Architect

Freelance Working and consulting for companies of different size and government institutions

01/2004 – 06/2004 BBJ Servis gGmbH Berlin, Germany

Software- & Database-Developer

09/2000 – 08/2003 Devcon Software GmbH Berlin, Germany

Trainee as "IT Specialist, Application Development"

**Publications** 

11/2011 "PopcornJS – Das HTML5-Media-Framework"

Webstandards magazine issue 12/2011 - 2 pages

Education

10/2009 – 09/2011 Humboldt University of Berlin Berlin, Germany

Study of Computer Science

08/2004 – 06/2008 Treptow-Kolleg Berlin, Germany

A-Level / Abitur

09/2000 – 08/2003 Devcon Software GmbH Berlin, Germany

Trainee as "IT Specialist, Application Development"

Others / Voluntary Activities

12/2009 – 06/2011 Recreational activities on weekends for groups of children with disability

06/2009 - 06/2013 Case work of child with disability

09/2008 – 05/2009 Civilian service at Helene-Häusler-Schule, special school

Interests & Skills

Languages German Native language

English Fluent

Hobbies & Interests Music, Photography, Design, Technology, Startups, FinTech